A Guide to the Papers of Ernest Hemingway, 1925-1961, n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series III: Miscellaneous Manuscripts
  - Wine List to Sherry's, New York, [1953], AMsS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 4:57)
    Composed on verso of envelope addressed to Ernest Hemingway from Charles Scribner's Sons. 6250-f
  - Contract"> 1959 April 23, DS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 4:58)
    Granting authority and rights to Edward Hotchner for theatrical programs based on his writings. Singed by Ernest Hemingway. 6250-f
  - Contract"> 1959 June, DS, bound, 7 pp. on 7 l (Box-folder 4:59)
    Ernest Hemingway authorizes Alfred Rice as the negotiator with CBS Television Network for the broadcasting of Hemingway's writings. Signed by Ernest Hemingway. 6250-f
  - Ernest Hemingway's summer itinerary, [1959], 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 4:60)
  - Interview with Ernest Hemingway, n.d., TMs carbon copy with autograph corrections, 10 pp. on 10 l. (Box-folder 4:61)
    Interview conducted in Hailey, Idaho at a local school. "Only copy of interview in existence." 6250-f
  - Various clippings regarding Ernest Hemingway, 1941-1963, n.d. (Box-folder 4:62)
    Hemingway is on the Way to the Far East for PM, 1941 January 31. For Whom is that Bell for, by Otis Ferguson, 1941 September 27 Mr. Hemingway's Finest Story Yet, by Dorothy Parker, [1941?] For Whom the Bell Tolls: A Condensation of the Picture Based on the Novel, [1943] Notes for a Hemingway Omnibus: The pattern of His Work and Its Relation to His Life, by Malcolm Cowley, 1944 September 23 The Position of Ernest Hemingway, by Ernest Hemingway and Maxwell Geismar, 1949 July 31 "Across the River and Into the Trees," Book Review, 195[0] September 7 Books: The Indignant Flesh, 1950 September 9 The Author's Name is Hemingway, by John O'Hara, 1950 September 10 Hemingway Portrait of an Old Soldier Preparing to Die, by Malcolm Cowley, 1950 September 10 'Hemingway is Bitter About Nobody' - But His Colonel Is, 1950 September 11 The New Hemingway, 1950 September 11 Talk with Mr. Hemingway, by Harvey Breit, 1950 September 17 Speaking of Books, by J. Donald Adams, 1950 September 24 "Books of The Times," by Charles Poore, 1950 September 30 "First Reviews of a New Book:Across the River and Into the Trees" from Jonathan Cape, n.d. Across the Street and Into the Grill, by E. B. W., n.d. Ernest Hemingway, [1950] Serious Americana, by Norah Hoult, n.d. Fictitious? [1950] "Books of The Times," by Charles Poore, [1950] Books and Things, by Lewis Gannett, [1950] To Have and To Have and To Have, by Maxwell Geismar, [1950] Parade of Books: Hemingway Writes a Farewell to Middle Age, by James Farber, [1950] "Across the River and Into the Trees," Book Review, Sterling North - World Telegram, [1950] O'Hara on Hemingway: How the Reader Felt About It, 1950 October 1 The Critics Have Never Been Easy on Ernest Hemingway, 1950 October 15 "Books of The Times," by Charles Poore, 1950 October 26 Hemingway and Steinbeck, by Norman Cousins, 1950 October 28 The Champ and the Referees, by Ben Ray Redman, 1950 October 28 A Titan to Task, by Harrison Smith, 1950 October 28 The Busted General, 1950 October When Hemingway Earned Half a Cent a Word on 'The Toronto Star,' by Herbert Cranston, 1952 January 13 Hemingway's Novel Has the Rich Simplicity of a Classic, by Malcolm Cowley, 1952 September 7 Trade Winds: Momentary Scoop, by Laura Hobson, 1952 August 23 "Books and Things: The Old Man and the Sea," by John K. Hutchens, 1952 August 28 A Line to the Heart, by Robert C. Ruark, 1952 August 28 "The Old Man and the Sea," Book Review, 1952 August 28 "Books of The Times," by Orville Prescott, 1952 August 28 "The Old Man and the Sea," LIFE Magazine advertisment Hemingway's Tragic Fisherman, by Robert Gorham Davis, 1952 September 7 Trade Winds: With Everybody Spewing Forth, [1952] The Marvel Who Must Die, by Carlos Baker, [1952] Old Man, by Max Lerner, [1952] The Old Man Lands Biggest Catch, LIFE Magazine, 1954 November 8 Farewell to Arms movie poster, 1958 January 8 "Hemingway spettatore di una corrida a Madrid," La Stampa, 1959 May 22 Determined Realist, by Mildred Adams, 1959 September 20 The Lyons Den by Leonard Lyons, 1959 December 28 Newspaper Images: Gary Cooper in For Whom the Bell Tolls and a scene from A. E. Hotchner's adaptation of The Gambler, the Nun and the Radio, 1960 May 15. Ernest Hemingway, [1961 July 3] Letters from Hemingway, by Frances Spatz Leighton, 1963 May 12 Ernest Hemingway, the Apostle by James T. Farrell, n.d. The Lyons Den: Lunch at Papa Hemingway's, by Leonard Lyons, n.d. The Current Cinema: Fish Story, n.d. Letters to the Editor, New York Times Book Review, n.d. Americans in Paris, by Janet Flanner, n.d. Scene from The Fifth Column, with Richard Burton and Sally Ann Howes 6250-u
- Series IV: Photographs, Slides and Portraits
  - Portrait of Ernest Hemingway by Henry Strater, [ca. 1922], 1 framed painting. (Box-folder 4:63)
    Includes copies and variations of portrait. Oversize Box F-2. 10247
  - Ernest Hemingway, [ca. 1926], photograph on postcard, 1 item. (Box-folder 4:64)
    7267-a
  - Ernest Hemingway, 1928 March 6, 1 photograph, signed. (Box-folder 4:65)
    Inscribed: "To Charles T. Scott with all best wishes from his friend." 6250-c
  - Ernest Hemingway, hunting and fishing, [ca. 1928], 3 photographs. (Box-folder 4:66)
    Originally enclosed in correspondence from Waldo Peirce to Harry Saltpeter, 1936 June 7. Photocopy of correspondence included. 8402
  - Portrait of Ernest Hemingway from magazine, [ca. 1928], 1 item. (Box-folder 4:67)
    With brief description of his literary fame. 6250-c
  - Ernest Hemingway, [ca. 1929?], 1 photograph, signed. (Box-folder 4:68)
    Inscribed: "To Charles Thomas Scott with all best wishes." 6250-c
  - Ernest Hemingway, 1933, 1937, n.d., 3 magazine photographs. (Box-folder 4:69)
    [1] Ernest Hemingway presents fourteen vivid storied in 'Winner Take Nothing,' mounted. (ca. 1933)
    [2] Hemingway (1937), mounted.
    [3] Hemingway at typewriter, n.d. Photograph courtesy of New York Public Library Picture Collection.
  - Ernest Hemingway, 1934-1959 (Box-folder 4:70)
    Includes original envelope enclosing photographs for E Hemingway.
    Hemingway being interviewed on board the Paris, April 3, 1934; Stork Club Victory Dinner after the 'battle with Max Eastman' August 13, 1937 (with Dave Smart, Sydney Franklin, and obscured John O'Hara); Hemingway with Martha Gellhorn at Stork Club, November 1940; Hemingway with Mary on the Flandre, June 24, 1953; Hemingway at interview on the Liberte, November 2, 1959; Hemingway at interview on the Liberte, November 2, 1959; Hemingway with Dean Stockwell, the actor on Liberte, November 2, 1959 10208-b
  - Ernest and Pauline Hemingway on ship, [ca. 1935], 1 photograph. (Box-folder 4:71)
    Photographed for Vanity Fair by Hoyningen-Huené. Clipped from Vanity Fair. 6250-c
  - Ernest Hemingway with Bronislaw Zielinski, 1958 November, 1 photograph (Box-folder 4:72)
    6250-g
  - Ernest Hemingway squatting by kill, n.d., 1 clipping (Box-folder 4:73)
    6250-c
  - Ernest Hemingway with Myrna Loy, William Powell, and Luise Ranier at Paramount Pictures, n.d., 1 photograph. (Box-folder 4:74)
    6250-w
  - Ernest and Mary Hemingway, n.d., 20 photographs (Box-folder 4:75)
    Mary Hemingway standing on stairs; Ernest and Mary; Mary holding dog (one 5x7; one 3x4); Ernest reading a newspaper; Ernest at a party, in background; Ernest next to car with unidentified man (one 5x7; one 3x4); Ernest reading paper outside with dog; Ernest standing indoors without shirt (two copies); Ernest at party holding fireman helmet upside down; Portrait of Ernest, close up; Ernest and Mary at fish market; Ernest opening gifts at birthday party with Mary and two other women; Ernest, facing away, at party; Ernest boxing by himself next to pool; Ernest swimming in pool; Ernest at party with fireman helmet and holding drink; Full portrait of Hemingway in front of his house (two copies) taken by A.E. Hotchner. 6250-i
  - Ernest and Mary Hemingway, n.d., 29 photographs (Box-folder 4:76)
    Mary with numerous cats (three 5x7 copies; one 3x4 copy); Ernest with gored bullfighter (three copies); Ernest standing with Spanish general with two men behind them (two copies); Ernest sitting next to lion skin and cat; mountains in background (two copies); Mary with cats; Ernest with mountains in background; Ernest with mountains in background, close up (three copies); Ernest with Ava Gardner and Luise Miguel Dominguín practicing with cape (5x7 and 3x4); Ernest and Mary walking down stairs; Ernest and Mary with another couple; Ernest with an unidentified woman (four copies); Ernest and Mary standing, with dog; Ava Gardner and Luise Miguel Dominguín at lunch table; Hemingway, outside, looking over stream; Ernest and Mary on stairs, with unidentified woman in foreground; Large crowd in Spain(?) 6250-i
  - Ernest and Mary Hemingway, n.d., 20 photographs (Box-folder 4:77)
    Ernest in hunting gear cleaning glasses (2 copies); Outdoor party (Hemingway's 60th birthday party?); Ernest and Mary pulling on wishbone; Ernest signing autograph at bullfight (4 copies); Ernest in car with unidentified woman; Ernest and Mary talking to unidentified man at picnic; Ernest and Mary looking at rocks; Ernest and Mary with two unidentified men preparing food on a hunt (three copies); Mary climbing over a barbed-wire fence; Ernest playing a record (two copies); Ernest watching Spanish dancers; Head portrait of Ernest (two copies) 6250-i
  - Ernest and Mary Hemingway, n.d., 14 photographs (Box-folder 4:78)
    * Ernest and Mary with unidentified couple in Southern France * Mary with unidentified couple in Southern France * Mary at farm with young Italian writer living with Ernest and Mary * Two cats * One cat * Unidentified boy on horse * Large crowd in Spain * Ernest outside stone door opening * White dove house * Mary outside by stair railing * Mary on farm * Cat playing with rope * Mary in doorway with cats * Mary next to wall in bull ring 6250-i
  - Ernest and Mary Hemingway, n.d., 26 photographs (Box-folder 5:1)
    * Outside of castle; no people * Ernest and Mary entering castle with unidentified couple * Ernest and group looking out from top of castle * Ernest and unidentified woman walking along river * Ernest sitting with two men on park bench * Ernest and Mary * Ernest with unidentified woman * Ernest with unidentified man in front of gated entrance * Ernest reading plaque * Cats on balcony * Cats * Bird * Mary with small dog * Ernest walking on path * Unidentified woman looking over high railing * Butcher in butcher shop * Mary with unidentified couple * Bird flapping wings * Two cats walking * Cat walking; cat sitting * Mary with bird in her hands * Mary with small dog * Mary in "cattle lean-to" on her farm * Mary putting bird on ground * Mary kneeling with cats * Mary playing with young cow 6250-i
  - Ernest, Mary Hemingway, Ava Gardner, and Luise Miguel Dominguín, n.d., 17 photographs (Box-folder 5:2)
    * Ernest in Nimes coliseum * Ernest hunting with three other men * Ernest with unidentified couple * Italian writer staying with Hemingway's, with cat * Mary with housekeeper's son on horse * Ernest with Ava Gardner * Ernest, Luise Miguel Dominguín, and Ava Gardner toasting at outside dinner; Mary in background * Ernest in front of mountain range * Ernest with Ava Gardner * Ernest in large group, including Mary, Ava Gardner, and Luise Miguel Dominguín * Bullfight practice (3 individual shots) * Ava Gardner with unidentified man drinking wine * Ernest in bull ring * Ernest, Ava Gardner, and Luise Miguel Dominguín * Scene from a bullfight 6250-i
  - Bull-fighting practice,> n.d., 25 photographs (Box-folder 5:3)
    6250-i
  - Bull-fight, n.d., 14 photographs (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Hemingway, hunting and fishing, n.d., In Their Time Exhibit Material (Reel 5:5)
    * Ernest with killed lion * Ernest squatting next to hornsof three killed animals * Ernest with large marlin in boat * 3 images of Ernest next to large marlin on dock
  - Ernest and Mary Hemingway, n.d., 4 negatives (Box-folder 5:6)
    * Ernest and Mary on boat * Ernest and Mary on boat * Mary in garden * Mary with cat in her arms 6250-i
  - Ernest and Mary Hemingway, Adriana Ivancich, and others, n.d., 10 proof sheets (Box-folder 5:7)
    * 35-181-A: 28 shots of Ernest, Mary, and other individuals in Spain (2 copies) * 35-181-B: 28 shots of Ernest, Mary and others out West (2 copies) * 35-181-C: 30 shots of Ernest and Mary hunting and sightseeing (1 copy) * 35-181-D: 20 shots of Ernest in Mary out West and in Europe (1 copy) * 4 shots of Adriana Ivancich (the model for Renata in Across the River and Into the Trees) * 4 shots: Adriana Ivancich; Ernest with Adriana; Ernest with unidentified man; Mary in front of bridge * 3 shots: Ernest, Mary, and Adriana Ivancich; Ernest with owl; Ernest with Spanish general * 4 shots: Hemingway in front of castle (2 views); Hemingway with three other men; Mary and unidentified man on farm 6250-i
  - Scene from The Killers, [ca. 1956], 1 photograph. (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Ernest Hemingway and Martha Hemingway, n.d., 3 photographs (Box-folder 5:9)
    Photographs by Robert Capa. * Ernest Hemingway at Sun Valley on a shooting trip taking a drink. * Ernest Hemingway holding a jack rabbit he killed (only to help farmers; doesn't eat). * Martha (Gelhorn) Hemingway soon after marriage seated on bed reading letter, ca. 1940 December. 6250-e
  - Ernest Hemingway and Martha Hemingway, n.d., 6 photographs (Box-folder 5:10)
    Photographs by Robert Capa. Ernest Hemingway and Martha (Gelhorn) Hemingway at Sun Valley on duck shooting trip -- Ernest Hemingway with ducks he killed. -- Ernest Hemingway waiting to shoot a duck. -- Ernest Hemingway shooting a duck. -- Ernest Hemingway and Martha (Gelhorn) Hemingway at Sun Valley in a house. -- Ernest Hemingway seated, writing. 6250-e
  - Don Ernesto in Pamplona, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:11)
    Original belongs to Mrs. Henry Louis Cohn. May not be reproduced without her permission. In Their Time Exhibit Material
  - Watercolor portrait of Ernest Hemingway by Alice Frymir, n.d., Based on photograph by Yousuf Karsh. Oversize box F-19 (Box-folder 5:12)
    Folder 13. Ernest Hemingway with others, n.d., 34 slides. 6250-i Slide 1: Ernest next to Palm Tree; Slide 2: Ernst on steps of church; Slide 3: Ernest in front of "Reptile Garden"; Slide 4: Ernest stepping into pool; Slide 5: Ernest swimming in pool; Slide 6: Ernest with unidentified man and woman; Slide 7: Ernest looking at book rack; Slide 8: Ernest by fountain; Slide 9: Ernest near ruins; Slide 10: Ernest near ruins; Slide 11: Ernest with mountains in background; Slide 12: Ernest with unidentified man; Slide 13: Ernest in garden with two men; Slide 14: Ernest at pool with man and woman; Slide 15: Ernest sitting with two women; Slide 16: Ernest at garden party; Slide 17: Ernest at garden party; Slide 18: Ernest sitting with two women and one man; Slide 19: Ernest with woman and another couple; Slide 20: Ernest at garden party; Slide 21: Ernest at pool with woman; Slide 22: Ernest at pool with woman; Slide 23: Ernest walking with package in hand; Slide 24: Ernest at "New Mexico Reptile Garden"; Slide 25: Ernest(?) in distance on bridge; Slide 26: Ernest(?) in field with cow; Slide 27: Ernest(?) in field with cow; Slide 28: Ernest with unidentified man; Slide 29: Ernest with unidentified woman; Slide 30: Ernest at pool party; Slide 31: Ernest in snow with unidentified man; Slide 32: Ernest with woman sitting on fence with mountains in background; Slide 33: Ernest arm in arm with unidentified man; Slide 34: Ernest swimming in pool with woman. 6250-b
- Series V: Audio and Video Recordings
  - [untitled] n.d., 16mm color film, silent. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Ernest Hemingway in Cuba.
    DVD available for public use in Robertson Media Center.
    Film F-157; videotape VC-18. 6250-i
  - Recordings of Ernest Hemingway, P-520 through P-525. (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Hemingway: A Portrait in Sound, 2 sound discs (Box-folder 5:16)
    P-607: Two 12-inch disks. 6250-l